<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss 
version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Decentralization Foundation Updates</title>
    <link>https://d24n.org/d24n-test/index.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[Feed for blog 'Decentralization Foundation Updates' generated by unstatic]]></description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 3 Feb 2023 15:21:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>https://github.com/swaldman/unstatic</generator>
    <docs>https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 13:08:05 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2022/01/25/grant-to-usp/index.html</guid>
      <author>nospam@dev.null (Chris Peel)</author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Jan 25 2022 Grant to University of São Paulo The Foundation has made a grant of $18,000 to the University of São Paulo (USP) for development of a technical credit-bearing course on blockchain and other decentralizing technologies to be offered at USP. An open version of the course will also be made available online to all, even those not enrolled at the university. Quoting our very first blog post “We want to educate this community and others on the underlying technology, including its potential and its limitations.” As a step in this direction, we started an effort last year to fund technical classes; the USP courses are the first results. Here is a quote from our grant agreement with USP (with some legalese removed): The credit-bearing course will be developed with the expectation of...]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2022/01/25/grant-to-usp/index.html</link>
      <title>Grant to University of São Paulo</title>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<article>
 <div class="article-header presentation-single">
  <div class="article-top-date">
   Jan 25 2022
  </div>
  <h1><a class="permalink" href="https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2022/01/25/index.html">Grant to University of São Paulo</a></h1>
 </div>
 <div class="article-body">
  <p>The Foundation has made a grant of $18,000 to the University of São Paulo (USP) for development of a technical credit-bearing course on blockchain and other decentralizing technologies to be offered at USP. An open version of the course will also be made available online to all, even those not enrolled at the university.</p>
  <p>Quoting our very <a href="https://d24n.org/2019/03/15/intro-d24n/index.html">first</a> blog post “We want to educate this community and others on the underlying technology, including its potential and its limitations.” As a step in this direction, we started an effort last year to <a href="https://d24n.org/2021/08/17/funding-technical-classes/">fund technical classes</a>; the USP courses are the first results. Here is a quote from our grant agreement with USP (with some legalese removed):</p>
  <blockquote>
   <p>The credit-bearing course will be developed with the expectation of becoming part of the curriculum of the Computer Engineering program offered at USP’s Escola Politécnica.</p>
   <p>The open version will be offered free for any interested party, even for those not enrolled at the university via USP’s official platforms for online courses (namely, <a href="https://eaulas.usp.br/">https://eaulas.usp.br/</a> and <a href="https://edisciplinas.usp.br/">https://edisciplinas.usp.br/</a>). All material (slides for lectures, lecture video recordings, lecture notes, syllabus, homework, and other support material) will also be made available for free online on a site that does not require creating a login for access.</p>
   <p>The course will be entirely built in Brazilian Portuguese, by native speakers.</p>
  </blockquote>
  <p>We are very happy to be working with Professor <a href="https://www.larc.usp.br/marcos-antonio-simplicio-junior/">Marcos Antonio Simplicio Junior</a> and others at USP on this project. We look forward to seeing the class materials!</p>
  <hr class="centered-black">
  <p>The Decentralization Foundation’s mission is to promote decentralizing technology, educate on its potential, and fund research to improve it. We are a 501(c)(3) non-profit and are funded by tax-deductible&nbsp;<a href="https://d24n.org/donate/">donations</a>.</p>
 </div>
 <div class="article-footer"><a class="permalink" href="https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2022/01/25/index.html">Published by Chris Peel on 2022-01-25</a>
 </div>
</article>]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2021/08/17/funding-technical-classes/index.html</guid>
      <author>nospam@dev.null (Chris Peel)</author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Aug 17 2021 Funding Technical Classes Updated 10 November 2022: The requirement that classes be in a language other than English was removed. d24n.org is looking for academic courses focused on decentralizing technology to fund with significant grants. We are especially interested in funding such courses in Latin America and in other locations where such grants would go farther and where a course in the local language would allow more people to learn about blockchain technology. We require that video and other course material be made available for free online. Education has been part of our mission from the start; quoting our first blog post “We want to educate this community and others on the underlying technology, including its potential and limitations.” We are open to courses that are...]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2021/08/17/funding-technical-classes/index.html</link>
      <title>Funding Technical Classes</title>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<article>
 <div class="article-header presentation-single">
  <div class="article-top-date">
   Aug 17 2021
  </div>
  <h1><a class="permalink" href="https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2021/08/17/index.html">Funding Technical Classes</a></h1>
 </div>
 <div class="article-body">
  <p style="font-size:smaller"><em>Updated 10 November 2022: The requirement that classes be in a language other than English was removed.</em></p>
  <p>d24n.org is looking for academic courses focused on decentralizing technology to fund with significant grants. We are especially interested in funding such courses in Latin America and in other locations where such grants would go farther and where a course in the local language would allow more people to learn about blockchain technology. We require that video and other course material be made available for free online.</p>
  <p>Education has been part of our mission from the start; quoting our first blog post “We want to educate this community and others on the underlying technology, including its potential and limitations.” We are open to courses that are not focused on the technology, such as those focused on cryptocurrency economics and sociology, though such will face more scrutiny during the review process. We believe that high-quality technical courses (such as those below) at universities are a great aid in building local communities that are knowledgeable about decentralizing technology.</p>
  <p>Here are examples of technical courses that we see as excellent models:</p>
  <ul>
   <li>“<a href="http://web.stanford.edu/class/ee374/">Internet-Scale Consensus in the Blockchain Era</a>” taught by David Tse at Stanford in 2021. The focus of this course is on blockchain consensus such as proof-of-work and proof-of-stake, which are analyzed in terms of throughput, efficiency, and security.</li>
   <li>“<a href="https://cs251.stanford.edu/syllabus.html">Bitcoin and Cryptocurrencies</a>” was taught by Dan Boneh at Stanford in 2020. This course covered blockchain basics, consensus protocols, and blockchain scaling. This has a broader focus than Tse. “<a href="https://soc1024.ece.illinois.edu/teaching/ece398sc/spring2018/">Smart Contracts and Blockchain Security</a>” by Andrew Miller at UIUC is a similar broadly-focused course.</li>
   <li>A technical cryptography course that focuses on other areas (one-way functions, public-key cryptography, zero-knowledge proofs) yet includes significant content on the basics of how a blockchain works is acceptable.</li>
  </ul>
  <p>In all cases we require that the course be taught in an academic setting, that video, syllabi, and homework be made available online, and that a connection with the community outside the academic setting be made (say local meetups). We require that such courses cover potential problems with the technology (e.g. energy efficiency and scalability). We are mainly interested in funding such courses in areas where English proficiency is not as high and where online material for a course in the local language would facilitate better understanding of blockchain technology.</p>
  <p>We believe that these technical courses would provide critical context for local cryptocurrency, IPFS, or similar communities in which a strong technical background is not common. Please go to <a href="https://d24n.org/index.html">d24n.org</a> and fill out an <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScBnYypFCEngFA4tc75_rUJLHbgUpcQPlMrZeRbCarGfxNNew/viewform">application</a>!</p>
 </div>
 <div class="article-footer"><a class="permalink" href="https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2021/08/17/index.html">Published by Chris Peel on 2021-08-17</a>
 </div>
</article>]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2021/05/13/lighthouse-research-report/index.html</guid>
      <author>nospam@dev.null (Chris Peel)</author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[May 13 2021 Lighthouse Research Report We are happy to share a report resulting from a grant made last year by the foundation to Sigma Prime for scientific research and development related to Ethereum 2 (Eth2). The report outlines challenges encountered and solutions found while implementing the Lighthouse Eth2 client. To illustrate the work, we list here a few items described in the report: A validator shuffling optimization which resulted in a 200x speedup (see page 5), An epoch processing optimization (page 6) The Lighthouse slasher (page 6) The Rust implementation of Gossipsub including an online scoring system (pages 7,8) Lighthouse client fuzzing (pages 8,9) Weak Subjectivity Sync (page 8) The report has a wonderful set of links to further material that we encourage you to...]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2021/05/13/lighthouse-research-report/index.html</link>
      <title>Lighthouse Research Report</title>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<article>
 <div class="article-header presentation-single">
  <div class="article-top-date">
   May 13 2021
  </div>
  <h1><a class="permalink" href="https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2021/05/13/index.html">Lighthouse Research Report</a></h1>
 </div>
 <div class="article-body">
  <p>We are happy to share a <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/12flM_E_A3DldbOUe8EYEN6Bg2bi4Yl6w/view?usp=sharing">report</a> resulting from a <a href="https://d24n.org/grant-to-sigma-prime-for-ethereum-2-research/">grant</a> made last year by the foundation to Sigma Prime for scientific research and development related to Ethereum 2 (Eth2). The report outlines challenges encountered and solutions found while implementing the <a href="https://github.com/sigp/lighthouse">Lighthouse</a> Eth2 client. To illustrate the work, we list here a few items described in the report:</p>
  <ul>
   <li>A validator shuffling optimization which resulted in a 200x speedup (see page 5),</li>
   <li>An epoch processing optimization (page 6)</li>
   <li>The Lighthouse <a href="https://hackmd.io/@sproul/min-max-slasher">slasher</a> (page 6)</li>
   <li>The <a style="font-family:-apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;" href="https://github.com/libp2p/rust-libp2p/tree/master/protocols/gossipsub">Rust implementation</a><span style="font-family:-apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;"> of Gossipsub</span> including an online scoring system (pages 7,8)</li>
   <li>Lighthouse client fuzzing (pages 8,9)</li>
   <li>Weak Subjectivity Sync (page 8)</li>
  </ul>
  <p>The report has a wonderful set of links to further material that we encourage you to investigate for further info on these topics. The end of the report highlights the “The Merge” in which Ethereum (and Lighthouse) will transition from proof-of-work to proof-of-stake:</p>
  <blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
   <p>In the coming year, we hope to be bringing The Merge into its final stages and hopefully production. The specification for The Merge is available <a href="http://In the coming year, we hope to be bringing The Merge into its final stages and hopefully production. The specification for The Merge is available here (inspired by this research post and still going through significant changes). The Merge is a very broad initiative involving the entire community, so it’s difficult for us to define a timeline, but we’re optimistic for a merge in late 2021.">here</a> (inspired by this <a href="http://In the coming year, we hope to be bringing The Merge into its final stages and hopefully production. The specification for The Merge is available here (inspired by this research post and still going through significant changes). The Merge is a very broad initiative involving the entire community, so it’s difficult for us to define a timeline, but we’re optimistic for a merge in late 2021.">research post</a> and still going through significant changes). The Merge is a very broad initiative involving the entire community, so it’s difficult for us to define a timeline, but we’re optimistic for a merge in late 2021.</p>
  </blockquote>
  <p>Additional info can be found in the <a href="https://lighthouse-book.sigmaprime.io">Lighthouse book</a>, by following the <a href="https://blog.sigmaprime.io/beacon-fuzz-09.html">Sigma Prime blog</a>, and by reading the report. We are grateful to Sigma Prime for their scientific research, their excellent work on the Lighthouse client, and for this research report.</p>
 </div>
 <div class="article-footer"><a class="permalink" href="https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2021/05/13/index.html">Published by Chris Peel on 2021-05-13</a>
 </div>
</article>]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Tue, 1 Dec 2020 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2020/12/01/an-economic-analysis-of-eip-1559/index.html</guid>
      <author>nospam@dev.null (Chris Peel)</author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Dec 01 2020 An Economic Analysis of EIP 1559 We are happy to share the report resulting from Professor Tim Roughgarden’s work on the Ethereum transaction price mechanism, including EIP 1559. The report is detailed yet accessible and educational summary of the proposal (variable-size blocks, the burned base fee) as well as an analysis of its strengths and weaknesses compared to the current mechanism and related proposals. The report is positive about EIP 1559, suggesting it meets the goals of easy fee estimation, lower variance on transaction fees, robustness to off-chain agreements by miners, and reduced inflation. Even so, there are some “Key Takeaways” which may be unexpected (see Section 1.2): 7. The seemingly orthogonal goals of easy fee estimation and fee burning are inextricably...]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2020/12/01/an-economic-analysis-of-eip-1559/index.html</link>
      <title>An Economic Analysis of EIP 1559</title>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<article>
 <div class="article-header presentation-single">
  <div class="article-top-date">
   Dec 01 2020
  </div>
  <h1><a class="permalink" href="https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2020/12/01/index.html">An Economic Analysis of EIP 1559</a></h1>
 </div>
 <div class="article-body">
  <p>We are happy to share the <a href="http://timroughgarden.org/papers/eip1559.pdf">report</a> resulting from Professor Tim Roughgarden’s <a href="https://d24n.org/tim-roughgarden-will-work-on-eip-1559/">work</a> on the Ethereum transaction price mechanism, including <a href="https://github.com/ethereum/EIPs/blob/master/EIPS/eip-1559.md">EIP 1559</a>. The report is detailed yet accessible and educational summary of the proposal (variable-size blocks, the burned base fee) as well as an analysis of its strengths and weaknesses compared to the current mechanism and related proposals.</p>
  <p>The report is positive about EIP 1559, suggesting it meets the goals of easy fee estimation, lower variance on transaction fees, robustness to off-chain agreements by miners, and reduced inflation. Even so, there are some “Key Takeaways” which may be unexpected (see Section 1.2):</p>
  <blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
   <p>7. The seemingly orthogonal goals of easy fee estimation and fee burning are inextricably linked, with the threat of off-chain agreements precluding one without the other. (Sections 8.1–8.2)</p>
   <p>8. EIP-1559’s base fee update rule is somewhat arbitrary and should be adjusted over time. (Section 8.4)</p>
   <p>9 Variable-size blocks enable a new (but expensive) attack vector: overwhelm the network with a sequence of maximum-size blocks. (Sections 8.4.5–8.4.6)</p>
  </blockquote>
  <p>Tim is Professor of Computer Science at Columbia University, and is a leading algorithmic game theorist. He has been awarded the ACM <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grace_Murray_Hopper_Award">Grace Murray Hopper Award,</a> the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/G%C3%B6del_Prize">Gödel Prize</a>, and many other awards. We are very grateful that he was willing to work on the Ethereum transaction price mechanism. We anticipate that his accessible writeup will act as an introduction and guide to Ethereum price mechanisms and bring attention to the academic world of the interesting and challenging problems found in Ethereum and other blockchains.</p>
  <p>We are very pleased with the <a href="http://timroughgarden.org/papers/eip1559.pdf">report</a>. Thank you Tim!</p>
 </div>
 <div class="article-footer"><a class="permalink" href="https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2020/12/01/index.html">Published by Chris Peel on 2020-12-01</a>
 </div>
</article>]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 21:25:11 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2019/03/15/intro-d24n/index.html</guid>
      <author>nospam@dev.null (Chris Peel)</author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Mar 15 2019 Introducing the Decentralization Foundation Update on 8 Apr 2019: We received our 501(c)(3) approval letter today! This allows tax-deductible donations from US taxpayers. It is an important step for the foundation. Original post: We are pleased to announce the launch of the Decentralization Foundation, with a mission of promoting decentralizing technology, educating the world on its potential, and funding relevant scientific research. The foundation will raise donations and fund projects and communities that are consistent with the mission. Why create the Decentralization Foundation? We want to build a community that is passionate about decentralization and is also willing to learn from others. We want to educate this community and others on the underlying technology,...]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2019/03/15/intro-d24n/index.html</link>
      <title>Introducing the Decentralization Foundation</title>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<article>
 <div class="article-header presentation-single">
  <div class="article-top-date">
   Mar 15 2019
  </div>
  <h1><a class="permalink" href="https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2019/03/15/index.html">Introducing the Decentralization Foundation</a></h1>
 </div>
 <div class="article-body">
  <p><strong>Update on 8 Apr 2019</strong>: We received our 501(c)(3) <a href="https://d24n.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/417a2-501c3approval.pdf">approval letter</a> today! This allows tax-deductible <a href="https://d24n.org/donate/">donations</a> from US taxpayers. It is an important step for the foundation.</p>
  <p><strong>Original post:</strong> We are pleased to announce the launch of the Decentralization Foundation, with a mission of promoting decentralizing technology, educating the world on its potential, and funding relevant scientific research. The foundation will raise donations and fund projects and communities that are consistent with the mission.</p>
  <p dir="ltr">Why create the Decentralization Foundation? We want to build a community that is passionate about decentralization and is also willing to learn from others. We want to educate this community and others on the underlying technology, including its potential and its limitations. We want to fund scientific projects to improve the technology and society that would otherwise not be funded.</p>
  <h3>What will the foundation do?</h3>
  <p dir="ltr">The first focus of the foundation is to support community organizations and events by funding venues, <a href="http://meetup.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">meetup.com</a> fees, and food for events. We will support groups focused on basic decentralized technology, as well as organizations and events focused on specific systems such as cryptocurrencies. We also plan to fund documentation of decentralized systems with the goal of making the technology more accessible to beginners. We are also happy to fund community events which include criticism of the decentralized technologies above. We will promote discussion of decentralization, economics, and social stability. We have already funded a small number of events, including an event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/EthereumSiliconValley/events/254358234/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">decompiling smart contracts</a>, and another on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/EthereumSiliconValley/events/254621281/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">formal verification of smart contracts</a>.</p>
  <p dir="ltr">One barrier to adoption of decentralized technologies is education. The second focus of the foundation is to develop and fund courses on important decentralized technologies such as hashes, Merkle trees, basic cryptography, and distributed consensus. We will also fund classes on systems such as Ethereum, Bitcoin, IPFS, and Circles, and finally courses on economics. We will promote a culture of critical thinking as a part of all curriculum.</p>
  <p dir="ltr">The final focus of the foundation will be on funding scientific research. We have already given a small grant to the <a href="https://www.kestrel.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kestrel Institute</a> which we will describe in a subsequent blog post.</p>
  <h3>Who are you? What are your goals?</h3>
  <p>I am Chris Peel, the president of the foundation. Steve Waldman is secretary and treasurer. Elaine Ou is a member of the board; Steve and I are also on the board. Jeff Flowers is vice president. See the foundation <a href="https://d24n.org/">website</a> for longer bios. These are smart, wonderful people; it is a privilege to work with and be educated by them.</p>
  <p>Our long-term goal with the foundation is to grow the decentralization-focused community. We are happy to work with big, well-established meetups, conferences, etc…; even more than this we would like to build communities and provide education in areas where there is none available at present.</p>
  <p>We acknowledge a long history of thinkers who have emphasized the value of decentralization; for example Tocqueville said:</p>
  <blockquote>
   <p>Decentralization has, not only an administrative value, but also a civic dimension, since it increases the opportunities for citizens to take interest in public affairs; it makes them get accustomed to using freedom.</p>
   <p style="text-align:right;"><i>“Democracy in America”, Alexis de Tocqueville, 1840, Saunders and Otley (London)</i></p>
  </blockquote>
  <p>We recognize that we are building on Tocqueville and many others who contributed to the <span style="color:var(--color-neutral-600);">discussion of decentralization in government, finance, ideology and more. Despite the breadth of work on decentralization, the foundation is</span><span style="color:var(--color-neutral-600);"> focused on technology, specifically the use of cryptography, blockchains, and incentives to build decentralized organizations. Steve will talk more about the word “decentralization” in a subsequent post.</span></p>
  <h3>Looking ahead</h3>
  <p dir="ltr">We have <a href="https://d24n.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/7840f-form-1023.pdf">applied</a> to the IRS for 501(c)(3) non-profit status in the US; if this is approved we will be able to accept tax-deductible donations. We are optimistic that our application will be approved.</p>
  <p dir="ltr">Finally, we are happy to announce a new round of grants; we are accepting applications now for small ($300-$3000) grants with a focus on community groups and meetups. Applications will close April 28. Please <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdT5tEz5j2NxRsrRsqBWgbRm814MiVAhrGbpxTzZSknUALfzQ/viewform">apply</a> or <a href="https://d24n.org/donate/">donate</a>!</p>
 </div>
 <div class="article-footer"><a class="permalink" href="https://d24n.org/d24n-test/2019/03/15/index.html">Published by Chris Peel on 2019-03-15</a>
 </div>
</article>]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="https://d24n.org/d24n-test/feed.rss"/>
  </channel>
</rss>
